<resources>
    <string name="app_name">geeeeek</string>


    <string name="Poseidon">
                Poseidon was god of the sea, earthquakes, storms, and horses. He is considered one of the most bad-tempered, moody and greedy Olympian gods. His vengeance when insulted was also legendary.
                He is the son of Cronus and RHEA and was swallowed by his father along with HADES, DEMETER, HESTIA and HERA. Legend has it that Cronus did this to prevent a prophecy in which one of his children would overthrow him. He was right to be cautions as Zeus later rescued Poseidon and his siblings, leading to the overthrow of Cronus and the establishment of the Olympian gods.
                Poseidon was portrayed as a strong, mature man with a dark beard, wielding a trident or (a three-pronged fisherman’s spear). He was moody by nature: his temperament was unstable at best, and his emotional fluctuations often resulted in violence.        </string>

    <string name="Zeus">
                Zeus is the Greek God of The Sky and Thunder and king of all the Gods. He was the first of the GODS and a very imposing figure. Often referred to as the “Father of Gods and men”, he is a sky god who controls lightning (often using it as a weapon) and thunder. Zeus is king of Mount Olympus, the home of Greek gods, where he rules the world and imposes his will onto gods and mortals alike.
                Zeus was the last child of the titans Cronus and RHEA, and avoided being swallowed by his father (who had been told one of his children would overthrow him) when Rhea sought help from URANUS and Gaea. Cronus had previously swallowed DEMETER, HESTIA, HERA, HADES and POSEIDON.
                Along with Hades and Poseidon, Zeus shared the rule of the world and became king of Olympus as the children of CRONUS were filled with admiration for their noble brother and sided with him against their unjust father – even following Zeus into The Battle of the Titans.
                Zeus mated with many GODDESSES and mortals (including Aegina, Alcmena, CALLIOPE, Cassiopea, DEMETER, Dione, Europa, Io, Leda, LETO, MNEMOSYNE, Niobe, PERSEPHONE and SEMELE) but was married to his sister Hera – goddess of marriage and monogamy.

        </string>

    <string name="Hades">
                The Underworld was a place where all human souls went after death. Contrary to popular belief, humans didn’t go the Greek equivalent of heaven. Elysian Fields, also known as ELYSIUM, was for heroes like PERSEUS and ACHILLES.
                In “The Iliad,” the Underworld dominion was between “Secret place on Earth.” However, the Homeric hymn, “The Odyssey,” described it as only accessible by crossing the ocean. Either way, the realm was separate from the land of the living, and one god resided over it. That god was Hades.
                Hades is the god of the Underworld and the dead. In ancient Greece, few dared to utter his name. If they did, many were referring to his realm, which many called “Hades” as well. The god was a brother to the TWELVE OLYMPIAN GODS. Though he was born at the same time and shared the same lineage as the other Olympian guardians, his realm was far below Mount Olympus.
        </string>

    <string name="Athena">
                Athena is a Greek goddess known as both Pallas and Athene. In ancient Greek mythology, they often associated her with both warfare and wisdom as well as handicraft, courage, inspiration, civilization, law and justice, strategic warfare, mathematics, strength, strategy, the arts, and skill.
                She also shares some things in common with Minerva from Roman mythology. Many refer to her as a protector or a patron of major cities such as Athens.
                She is known most specifically for her strategic skill in warfare and is often portrayed as companion of heroes and is the patron goddess of heroic endeavour.
                Athena was born from ZEUS after he experienced an enormous headache and she sprang fully grown and in armour FROM HIS FOREHEAD.
                She has no mother but one of the most commonly cited stories is that Zeus lay with METIS, the goddess of crafty thought and wisdom, and then swallowed her whole as he feared she will give birth to a child more powerful than him because of a prophecy – but she had already conceived.
        </string>

    <string name="Apollo">
                Apollo is one of the most complex and important gods, and is the god of many things, including: music, poetry, art, oracles, archery, plague, medicine, sun, light and knowledge.
                He is one of the of the TWELVE OLYMPIAN DEITIES
                He is the son of ZEUS and the TITAN LETO, and was born in the Greek island of Delos, along with his older twin sister ARTEMIS – goddess of the hunt.
                Apollo is the ideal of the kouros, which means he has a beardless, athletic and youthful appearance. He is also an oracular god as a patron of Delphi and could predict prophecy through the Delphic Oracle Pythia.
                Both medicine and healing are associated with Apollo and were thought to sometimes be mediated through his son, Asclepius. However, Apollo could also bring ill-health and deadly plague.
                Apollo also became associated with dominion over colonists, and as the patron defender of herds and flocks. He was the leader of the Muses (also known as Apollon Musegetes) and was director of their choir – functioning as the patron god of music and poetry.
                HERMES, the greek god of trade, eloquence and messenger of the gods, created the lyre for Apollo. This instrument became a known attribute for him. When hymns were sung to Apollo they were called paeans ( not the GREEK GOD PAEAN )
                At the drinking parties held on Olympus, Apollo accompanied the Muses on his cithara, while the young goddesses led the dance. Both Leto and Zeus were proud of their son, who was radiant with grace and beauty.
                Apollo was one of the few gods that the ROMANS KEPT THE SAME NAME.  In Greek mythology, he was most widely known as the god of light. Within Roman mythology, he wasn’t known as much as the god of light and was focused mainly as the god of healing and prophecy.
        </string>

    <string name="Ares">
               Ares is the god of war, one of the Twelve OLYMPIAN GODS and the son of ZEUS and HERA. In literature he represents the violent and physical untamed aspect of war, which is in contrast to ATHENA who represents military strategy and generalship as the goddess of intelligence.
                Although Ares embodied the physical aggression necessary for success in war, the Greeks were ambivalent toward him because he was a dangerous, overwhelming force that was insatiable in battle.
                He is well known as the lover of APHRODITE, who was married to HEPHAESTUS, and though Ares plays a limited role in literature, when he does appear in myths it is typically facing humiliation. For example, one famous story of Ares and Aphrodite exposes them to ridicule by the gods when her husband Hephaestus trapped them both naked in a bed using a clever device he made.
                The ROMAN COUNTERPART to Ares was MARS, who was known as a FATHER TO THE ROMAN PEOPLE. Because of this, he was a less aggressive and physical form, revealing a more calm and understanding demeanour.
        </string>

    <string name="Artemis">
               Greek mythology is filled with respected gods and goddesses that continue to inspire. Artemis is known as the goddess of the hunt and is one of the most respected of all the ancient Greek deities. It is thought that her name, and even the goddess herself, may even be pre-Greek. She was the daughter of ZEUS, king of the gods, and the TITANESS LETO and she has a twin brother, the god APOLLO.
                Not only was Artemis the goddess of the hunt, she was also known as the goddess of wild animals, wilderness, childbirth and virginity. Also, she was protector of young children and was know to bring and relieve disease in women. In literature and art she was depicted as a huntress carrying a bow and arrow. She was the goddess of many things, but most remember her as the most recognizable of the hunting deities.
                Artemis was a virgin and drew the attention and interest of many gods and men. However, it was only her hunting companion, Orion, that won her heart. It is believed that Orion was accidentally killed either by Artemis herself or by GAIA, the primordial goddess of the earth.
                In one version of the stories of ADONIS – who was a late addition to Greek mythology during the Hellenistic period – Artemis sent a wild boar to kill Adonis after he continued to boast that he was a far greater hunter than her.
        </string>

    <string name="Aphrodite">
                Aphrodite, the Greek goddess of love, beauty, and desire, stands as one of the most captivating and influential deities in ancient Greek mythology. Her origins though, are shrouded in mystery.
                According to Hesiod’s THEOGONY, she emerged from the sea foam in the waters of Paphos, on the island of Cyprus, born from the severed genitals of Uranus. She supposedly arose from the foam when THE TITAN CRONUS slew his father Uranus and threw his genitals into the sea.
                However, according to Homer, in Iliad, Aphrodite may instead be the daughter of ZEUS and Dione. As with so many Greek deities, there are many stories about the origins of the gods.
        </string>

    <string name="Hera">
                She is known for being the Goddess of Marriage and Birth. Despite being the Goddess of Marriage, she was known to be jealous and vengeful towards the many lovers and offspring of her husband Zeus.
                She was also known to turn her anger towards mortals who crossed her as well – for example, Paris, who chose APHRODITE over Hera as the most beautiful goddess at the marriage of the sea-nymph Thetis to a mortal called PELEUS.
                In images and STATUES, Hera is portrayed as being majestic and solemn, crowned with the polos – a high cylindrical crown worn by many of the Great Goddesses.
                Even before her marriage with Zeus, she ruled over the heavens and the Earth. This is one reason why she is referred to as ‘The Queen of Heaven’ – ruling over Mount Olympus where all the gods and GODDESSES live.
        </string>

    <string name="Hermes">
                Hermes was one of the 12 Olympian Gods and was god of trade, thieves, travelers, sports, athletes, and border crossings, guide to the Underworld. He was the second youngest Olympian god and was the SON of ZEUS and MAIA, one of the seven Pleiades and daughter of the TITAN ATLAS.
                As the god of boundaries and transitions, Hermes was known to be quick and cunning and had the ability to freely move between the mortal and divine worlds. It is this skill that made him a luck-bringing messenger to the gods and intercessor between mortals and the divine.
                He is also the patron and protector of travelers, herdsmen, thieves, orators and wit, literature and poets, athletics and sports, invention and trade. In some myths Hermes is also depicted as a trickster where he would outwit the gods either for the good of humankind or for his own personal amusement and satisfaction.
                Both Homer and Hesiod portrayed Hermes as the author of skilled or deceptive acts, and also as a benefactor of mortals.
        </string>

    <string name="Dionysus">
                Dionysus was the ancient Greek god of wine, winemaking, grape cultivation, fertility, ritual madness, theater, and religious ecstasy. His Roman name was Bacchus. He may have been worshiped as early as 1500-11000 BCE by Mycenean Greeks. As wine was a major part of ancient Greek culture, Dionysus was an important and popular figure in mythology. He was one of the twelve Olympians, although he was the last to arrive, and his unusual birth and upbringing marked him as an outsider.
                Earlier images and descriptions of Dionysus depict him as a mature male, bearded and robed holding a fennel staff tipped with a pine-cone. However, in later images the god is show to be a beardless, sensuous, naked or semi-naked androgynous youth. He is described in literature as womanly or “man-womanish”.
                He was the son of ZEUS and the mortal Semele, making Dionysus semi-device or a hero.
        </string>

    <string name="Hephaestus">
                Hephaestus was the god of fire, metalworking, stone masonry, forges and the art of sculpture. He was a son of ZEUS and HERA and married to APHRODITE. Zeus enforced this marriage to prevent a war of the gods fighting for her hand. He was a smithing god, making all of the weapons for Olympus and acting as a blacksmith for the gods.
                He had his own palace on Olympus where he made many clever inventions and automatons of metal to work for him. Hephaestus’s ugly appearance was one of the main reasons Zeus chose him to marry Aphrodite.
                Known for his skill in the forge and creating wondrous artefacts, Hephaestus’ story is one of resilience, creativity, and the complexities of divine relationships. Despite his physical imperfections and ugliness, he was revered for his craftsmanship. He was an essential deity in the pantheon of Olympus.
                In some ways he is similar to ATHENA, in that he used his skills to help mortals – in his case artists. It was believed that he taught men the arts alongside Athena. However, he was also considered far inferior to the goddess of wisdom.

        </string>

    <string name="Demeter">
                Demeter is the goddess of the harvest and presides over grains and the fertility of the earth. Although she was most often referred to as the goddess of the harvest, she was also goddess of sacred law and the cycle of life and death.
                She is a very important deity in the Greek pantheon, embodying the life-giving aspects of nature and overseeing the cycles of life, death, and rebirth. Her myths and worship reflect the ancient Greeks’ deep connection with the land and their understanding of the delicate balance of the natural world.
                Demeter’s influence extended into the realm of sacred law and rites, particularly through the Eleusinian Mysteries – a series of large and secretive concerts held every five years. These mysteries represented the abduction of Persephone by Hades in three phases. The “descent” (loss), the “search” and the “ascent”. The main theme is the “ascent” of Persephone and the reunion with her mother. These secretive and mystical rites, held in her honor, promised initiates guidance for a blessed afterlife.
        </string>


</resources>